他们怎么会没接到我们的预订
How the hell did they lose our reservation.
老爸  你跟老妈结婚三十年
Dad, you were married to mom for thirty years.
只不过是再睡几天沙发而已
It's just a couple of nights on the couch.
我要给会议主办方打电话
I'm gonna call for the Con.
让酒店退9.95元的无线网费用
I'm gonna try to squeeze them on that $9.95 wifi fee.
不就是在卖空气嘛
They're selling air.
橱柜展销会是北美橱柜行业
ClosetCon is the premier north American trade show
第一大展销会
for the closet industry.
我几年前开始不再参加
I stopped going years ago
因为这是"出"柜行业的展销会
'cause it's a trade show for the closet industry.
谢谢
Thank you.
会议安排得实在太棒了
This schedule is incredible.
老爸  10点45有一个关于
Dad, there's a 10:45 session
永续材料的会议
on sustainable materials.
我们一定得去
We have got to hit that.
但是跟11点的镶板研讨小组冲突了
Mm, but it overlaps with the 11:00 a.m. panel on paneling.
还有鞋架分会
And a breakout session on shoe storage.
给你点小建议
Little advice --
那些会议都是给菜鸟开的
the convention floor is for suckers.
真正的工作都是在酒吧里完成的
All work is done at the bar --
除非托尼和蕾拉在唱流行歌曲
Unless Tony G. and Layla are singing standards,
那样的话  别工作了  尽情欣赏吧
in which case, no work -- prepare to be entertained.
老爸  我是来这里学习的
Dad, I came here to learn,
不是上酒吧喝酒的
not sit at the bar and drink.
你爱干嘛干嘛  我要去喝杯威士忌
You do what you want. I'm getting a scotch.
我该去认识认识大家
Well, I do need to meet everybody.
好棒啊  吃早餐
Ooh, good. Breakfast.
还早餐呢  叫午餐比较合适吧
Breakfast? Try lunch.
-我们农场人起床早  -必须的
- We wake up early on the farm. - Sure do.
城里来的贪睡小耗子终于起来了
There's our sleepy city mouse.
我来帮你戴餐巾
Let's get you all squared away here.
我自己来  不用了  我自己来
Yeah, I-I got it. No, I got it.
放下面  这样就好  没事了
Down here. I'm good. I'm good. Now, I know --
我都忘了
You know, I forgot how
这里有这么多农活要干了
much work there was to be done around here.
我上午一直在修栅栏[双关:改善关系]
I've been mending fence all morning.
一直在修  真的吗
Been mending, have you?
密苏里
Missouri.
痛苦之地
Misery.
-好大的猪圈啊  -真可爱
- What a pig sty, huh? - Cute.
老爸去城里了  他要到晚饭时候才回来
Daddy went to town, he's gonna be there till super,
所以我在帮妈妈喂猪
so I'm helping mama slop the pigs.
你要来贡献点力量吗
You want to -- you want to pitch in?
不知道  我刚刚吃了培根  所以
I don't know, I just ate that bacon, so...
去喂猪似乎不太合适
How's that gonna look?
要不要敲响开饭铃  小超声波
Want to ring the dinner bell, "Little bomber"?
那说起来很古雅呢
Oh, that's actually really quaint.
是那种小三角形状的...
Is it one of those little triangle thi--
三郡范围内最响亮的吆喝
Loudest call in the tri-county area.
再来一次
Do it again!
不要了  亲爱的  一次就够了
No, sweetheart. I think once was enough.
还真有畜生朝这声音跑来的
There's actually an animal that runs toward that sound, huh?
翻译：小饭  四方虾  冰蓝  王大可  慕秋雪
时间轴：加森    校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第八集
你们好啊
Hello, hello!
-你预约了吗  -预约了  7点的
- Did you make the reservation? - Yeah, 7:00.
跟这个小家伙一起享用牛排晚餐
Fun family time with this little newsy
度过美好的家庭时光
and a steak dinner.
谁说去参加橱柜大会的人才有美好时光
Who says people at the closet convention get all the fun?
没人  没人那么说
No one. No one says that.
我告诉你  我去开门时
I am telling you, the way he looked at me
他看着我的样子  绝对是迷上我了
when I came to the door -- it is so on.
看起来就是他来送披萨
Kind of seemed like he was just delivering pizza,
你得付钱的样子呗
and you were giving him money.
你们在说什么呢
What are you guys talking about?
查克  昨晚送披萨的小伙子
Chuck, the pizza guy from last night.
他害羞但是很体贴
He's shy and thoughtful
穿着一件普林斯顿运动衫
and wears a Princeton sweatshirt --
完全不是海莉喜欢的型
Hardly Haley's type.
天呐  你爱上他了
Oh, my God. You love him.
什么  才没有  你怎么会说我爱上他
What? No! I d-- how would you say I love him?
他才来过家里三次
He's been to our house exactly three times.
太荒谬了  海莉  别看我
That's ridiculous, Haley! Don't even look at me.
太傻了
This is so stupid.
她爱上他了
She loves him.
曼尼汉子  照相日怎么样
Hey, "Manimal." How was picture day?
你知道什么对我帮助最大吗
You know what's super-helpful?
就是站在你后面的家伙叫你"大汗山"
When the guy in line behind you calls you "Mount Sweatmore."
我那是想让你放松点
I was trying to relax you.
多简单的梗
It was right in front of you
应该叫"布拉德・皮特汗渍"
-- "Brad Pitt-Stains."
-真不给力  卢克  -没关系啦
- Come on, Luke. - It's okay.
新的安保系统吗
New security system?
你可以看到后院
You can see the backyard,
前门  车库  全都看得到
the front door, the garage -- everywhere.
是啊  自从老妈生下
Yeah, can't take any chances
那边那颗希望钻石
since mom gave birth to
家里就不能冒任何风险
the hope diamond over there.
杰家里的厨房边上有一个房间
There is a room off the kitchen at Jay's house
总是锁着
that's always locked.
我每次过去都要试着开一次
I try it every time I'm there.
我花了无数时间  幻想那个房间里
I've spent countless hours imagining that that room
藏着一屋子的宝藏
is a house of treasure...
一座充满奇迹的宫殿
a palace of ceaseless wonder.
是真的
It's real.
你好啊  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
看到那个了吗
Would you look at that?
什么  简直太棒了
What?! That's coconuts!
不是吧
No!
那是
Is that --
阿波罗13号的复制品
A replica of Apollo 13.
瞧这细节
Look at the detail.
你都能看到宇航员在里头
You can almost see the astronauts
喝超小杯的果珍
drinking teeny, tiny Tang.
-能让我拿一下吗  -不行
- Can I hold it? - No.
你知道这有多珍贵吗
You have any idea how valuable this is?
你的手指上还有芝士粉末
And your fingers are covered in cheese dust.
这样
There.
-别  卢克  拜托  -你俩别闹了
- No! Luke, please! - Hey, guys. Knock it off.
别担心  歌洛莉亚  我能行
Don't worry, Gloria. I got it.
大家都别慌
Nobody panic!!
这可是收藏家版本  40年历史呢
This is a collector's edition. It's 40 years old!
我们得立即修复它
We're gonna have to improvise.
歌洛莉亚  给牛排馆打电话取消预约
Gloria, call the steakhouse and cancel.
曼尼  找些胶水来
Manny, find some glue.
卢克  我们把这些零部件都拿到车库
Luke, let's get these parts into the garage.
我知道这看起来很困难
I know this seems impossible,
但我们一定能行
but we can do this!
是休斯顿牛排馆吗[休斯顿火箭中心]
Hello. Houston's?
我们出了点状况
We have a situation.
我们是参加橱柜展的  哪都能进
Hi. We're with ClosetCon. All-access.
她不在乎  你是唯一戴着牌子的笨蛋
She doesn't care. You're the only dope wearing that here.
-快给我  -不  我喜欢
- Give it to me. - No. I like it.
好啊  乔尔
Hey. Joel.
看起来不错啊  老朋友
Looking good, my friend.
在自动化橱柜上洗澡
Took a bath on automated closets.
人们还没准备好呢
People aren't ready for that.
杰・普里契特  帅哥快过来
Jay Pritchett. Get your cute butt over here.
-她是谁  -一位老朋友
- Who's that? - An old friend.
我去打个招呼  你去拿两杯酒来吧
I'm gonna go say hello. Why don't you get us a couple drinks?
好  我这就去
Yeah. I'll do that.
能给我一杯威士忌和一杯白葡萄酒吗
Hi. Can I get a scotch and a white wine?
人真多  好吵啊
Wow, rowdy crowd, huh?
展销会嘛  人们离开家人
Trade shows -- people get away from their families,
-喝点小酒  -我懂的
- get a little liquored up. - Yeah, I get that.
你挂上了名牌
Let's just say when the nametags go on,
就该摘下婚戒了
the wedding rings come off.
我不大同意那点
I am not so on board with that.
好啊美女
Hey, there.
经典
Classy.
我帮你理理领带  看起来真帅
Let me just fix this. You're looking so great.
我妈妈比较以自我为中心
My mom was pretty self-involved,
而我爸经常出差
and my dad traveled a lot for work.
我的确想过...  你懂的
So, yeah, I did wonder if... you know.
我不是要责怪他
And not that I could blame him.
但每天我朋友艾莉森放学时
My friend Alison's mom
她妈妈都会用一个大大的拥抱
greeted her every day after school
和笑容迎接她
with a big hug and a giant smile,
我总是想  "是啊
And I always thought, "Yeah...
那样也挺不错的"
wouldn't mind a piece of that."
-要这样做吗  -我下午带去你房间里
- So, are we doing this? - I'll bring it to your room this afternoon.
对于新来橱柜展的人  我们有个小传统
We have a little tradition at ClosetCon for rookies,
今年是克莱尔
which Claire is this year.
我们把一具骨架藏在他们的橱柜里
We take a skeleton. We hide it in their closet.
他们打开柜门  然后大声尖叫
They open the door and scream,
我们大家都哄堂大笑
and we all have a good laugh.
这主意不是我们想出来的
Can't take full credit for the idea.
是从壁橱展上学的
We stole it from CabinetCon.
热苹果酒
Hot cider.
好  谢谢你  巴布
Oh, yes. Thank you, Barb.
-太感谢你了  -外面好冷
- Thank you so much. - It's chilly.
这酒真带劲
Mmm. Wow, that's got a kick.
那是朗姆酒的力道
That'll be the rum.
我能感受到它温暖你的小肚肚
I can feel it warming up your belly.
还在我嘴里和喉咙里呢
Yeah, still in my mouth and throat.
那是什么
Well, what's that?
开始变冷了啊
Boy, it starting to get nippy, huh?
你们想走去野鸭池塘吗
You guys want to walk down to the duck pond?
听起来挺不错的  我去拿枪
Um -- that sounds lovely. I'll get the gun.
-大家伙儿都来吗  -大家伙儿
- Are y'all coming? - "Y'all"?
-我们不说大家伙儿  -我们说的
- We don't say "Y'all"! - Yeah, we do.
我们在这里说  但一般不说
No, well, yeah, we say it... here, but not normally.
你觉得我其实是这样说话的
Well, did you ever think this is how I really talk
我离开这里时  说的话就不一样了吗
and that I talk different-like when I'm not here?
大家伙儿在吵架吗
Y'all fighting?
不不  亲爱的  我们只是在聊天
No, no, sweetie, we're just having a conversation
聊你二爸有多么高傲
about how your daddy can be so stuck-up.
小卡  你真"成熟"
Cam, that's really mature.
利用我们的女儿来挖苦我
Use our daughter to get your little digs in.
我绝不会那样做的  亲爱的
I would never do that, sweetie.
你觉得我没发现
You don't think I notice
我们来这里后你有多高傲吗
how condescending you are when we come here?
你"作"在门廊上  翻白眼
You just set on the porch. You roll your eyes.
什么也不参与
You don't participate in anything.
对  我说的是"作"
And, yeah, I said "Set."
但我们这里就是这样说话的
But that's how we talk here.
这里是我的家乡  我为它感到骄傲
I'm from this place. I'm proud of this place.
我很难过我爱的人觉得这是个大笑话
And it hurts me that the man I love just thinks it's some big joke.
走吧  亲爱的
Come on, sweetie.
仁慈的主啊
Lord a'mercy.
我饿死了  晚餐怎么办啊
Ugh. I'm starving. What are we gonna do about dinner?
我问过爸爸了  订了几块西奥家的匹萨
I checked with dad, and I ordered a couple pizzas from Theo's.
我就知道  你在跟踪我的匹萨帅哥
I knew it! You're stalking my pizza guy!
他不喜欢你  好吗
He is not into you, okay?
他叫过你"棕眼姑娘"吗
Does he call you "Brown eyes"
多给过你酥炸芝士条吗
and give you extra mozzarella sticks?
够了  你俩
Okay, that's it, you two!
你们不能像争珠宝或者鞋子一样争男人
You cannot fight over men like it's jewelry or shoes.
如果你俩都喜欢他  谁也不许去追
If you're both interested, no one makes a move.
姐妹第一  男人第二
Sisters before misters!
-跟踪狂  -荡妇
- Stalker! - Trollop.
不知道那是什么意思
Ha-ha, don't know what it means --
-你做了什么  -我没做什么
- What did you do?! - Nothing!
就是你  你把它打开了
Aah! Yes, you did! You turned it on,
现在螺旋桨都缠在一起了
and now the propeller's all tangled up!
我为什么要那样做
Why would I do that?
因为我的匹萨帅哥就要来了
'cause my pizza guy is coming,
现在我头发里有一架飞机
and now I have airplane in my hair!
我发誓我没有  海莉
I swear I didn't, Haley. Okay.
我来帮你弄出来  天啊
I'll get it out. Oh, my god, ow!
-发生什么了  -我不知道
- What is happening?! - I don't know!
你找到了一个小玩具吗
Ohh, you find a little toy?
刚在车道上
Hey, was that aunt Marge
横冲直撞的是玛吉姑妈吗
just tearing down the driveway?
对  她带来了一份小"礼物"
Yes. And she dropped off a little present.
这是我的小卡卡吗
Is that my Cam Cam?
-奶奶  -你好啊
- Gram gram! - Oh, you.
最近发布了风暴预警
There have been some storm warnings,
玛吉觉得她在这里更加安全
so Marge thought she'd be safer over here.
但她很快让她下了车
But she dropped her off so fast
我们都没时间整理一下[straight暗指直男]
that we didn't even have a chance to straighten up.
我们从没和奶奶说基佬的事
We never told gram about the gay.
他们年事已高
You know, after they reach a certain age,
可能听到了这件事
you worry that it could
一激动就一命呜呼了
be the thing that sends them over the edge,
而她已经随时都可能驾鹤西去了
And she's been on the edge for a long time.
实际上她排在二号临终床上
We're actually on deathbed number two.
米奇尔  米奇尔
Mitchell. Mitchell.
好吧  这怎么回事
Okay. W-what's this?
这是我准备好去喂猪  打包或者挤奶了
This is me ready to slop, bale, or milk something.
你没必要这样做
You don't need to do that.
不  小卡  我知道
No, I -- Cam, I-I know.
我知道我对你真实的一面过于苛责
I know I gave you hell for being who you really are,
-我想补偿你  -好吧  但你知道吗
- and I want to make that up to you. - Yeah, but you know what?
穿上我姐姐的周日工作服就足够了
Putting on my sister's Sunday overalls is gesture enough.
-这是什么  -我咀嚼的稻草
- What's this? - Oh, it's my chewing straw.
-这不是稻草  -这只是作秀啦
- It's not straw. - Oh, it's just show -- for show.
-别过去  别过去  -你爱这个男人
- Hey. Come on, come on. - You know, you love the man,
-要爱他的家乡  -是  但你知道吗
- you love the world he comes from. - Yeah, but you know what?
我不知道是这套农场装还是其它的缘故
I don't know if it's these farming clothes or what,
此时此刻我觉得和你好亲近
but I am feeling so close to you right now.
-这话真贴心  -快亲我一下
- Well, that's so sweet. - Now give me a kiss.
不行  现在不行
No, not right now.
别逼我扑倒你
Well, don't make me rassle you down.
这人是谁
Who's this?
惨了
Oh, dear.
奶奶  这位是巴德  新来的农工
Uh...well, grams, this is Bud, our new farmhand.
巴德
Bud?
是的  巴德脑袋被驴踢过
Yeah, Bud's a little simpleminded
所以脑子有点不好使  是不是
on account of getting mule-kicked, isn't he?
巴德  你该知道你是不能进屋的
And you know the rules on being in the house, Bud.
快出去吧
Now, go on outside.
我们过一会儿还得挤牛奶呢
We're gonna milk the cows in a few minutes.
出去挤奶吧  挤完请你吃饭
Get on out there. Have a treat afterwards.
所有零件都在这里了
Here's what we've got to work with.
干得漂亮  我已经和佛罗里达州连线了
Nicely done. I've got Florida on the line.
爸  我把你放到这里  你是模型专家
Dad, I'm flying you in. You're the model expert.
儿子  我们要组装什么东西
What are we looking at, son?
我的神呐
Holy Moses.
这是碎成1300块的阿波罗号啊
More like Apollo 1,300 pieces!
看来太空里的人没有什么幽默感
In space, I guess no one can hear you be hilarious.
我需要你专心一点
I need you to focus.
-万一杰看到这个...  -我知道了
- If Jay sees this... - I know!
爸  这里三个好男人全都靠你了
Dad, you've got three good men here depending on you.
不多说了  我现在要按一个键
Say no more -- I'm gonna tap a button now
可能会把我屏幕上
that's either gonna make you
你们的影像放大  或者
larger on my screen or --
我们和佛罗里达失去联系了
We've lost Florida.
现在就把骷髅架拿过来  我刚到房间
Yeah, yeah. Bring the skeleton up now. I just got to the room.
你好呀  爸
Hey, dad.
你好  女儿
Hey, honey.
我还以为我们是约在餐厅见呢
I thought we were meeting at the restaurant.
没错  那场演讲结束得有些早
Yeah, well, the lecture got done a little early,
而且我似乎成了今晚的明星
and I was kind of the star of the evening.
我杜撰出来一个词引得全场爆笑
I got a huge laugh when I coined the phrase
"柜尊"[与自尊近似]
"Shelf-esteem."
好笑吧
Huh? Yeah?
我得发短信告诉菲尔
Okay, I'll text it to Phil.
你何不到楼下大厅去发  信号会比较好
Why don't you go down to the lobby? You'll get a stronger signal.
-你好  -丽塔
- Oh. Hello. - Rita.
-这是我女儿  克莱尔  -你好
-This is my daughter, Claire. - Hi.
克莱尔  这位是丽塔
Claire, this is Rita.
我和你爸认识好多年了
Your dad and I go way back.
第一次见面的时候  我就告诉他
First time we met, I told him
他得进修一下"衣架"管理课程
he needed a course in "Hanger" Management.
[原词是anger management:愤怒管理]
现在回想都挺逗的
It's still funny.
说真的吗
Seriously?
她老公是从事服装生意的
Her husband's in the garment business.
他给我做了套西服
He made me a suit.
我做衣柜  他做衣柜里面的衣服
I make the closets, and he fills them.
天作之合
Match made in heaven.
那个餐厅里的人都很难缠
Honey, they're kind of sticklers at that restaurant.
要不你先去占座  我把这个放到屋里
Why don't you grab our table? I'll put this in the room.
好的  这就去
Uh, okay. Will do.
非常高兴见到你
Um, really nice to meet you.
楼下见了
See you downstairs.
我其实想走楼梯
I actually am gonna take the stairs.
电梯实在太慢了
That elevator is slow.
是我多想了
Hey, was it just me,
还是她看我的眼神确实有点怪
or was she looking at me weird?
我也有点感觉
I did kind of sense that.
她不会是知道了我们的事情吧
You don't think she knows about our deal?
怎么会  那件事都过去20年了
How could she? It was 20 years ago.
何况我从来没告诉过别人
And I never told anyone.
她还会介意这个吗
Would she even care?
介意我试图拆散她和她嫁的那个男人吗
That I tried to get rid of the man she ended up marrying?
你又没有攻击那个男人
Well, it's not like you took a hit out on him.
你只不过是让我给他
You had me offer him a job
在最好的州找了份工作
in the greatest state in the union.
好了  德克萨斯粉丝
Okay, Tex.
我从没对谁说过  她怎么会知道
If I never said anything, how could she know?
我第一个找上的人不是你
You're not the first one I approached.
你只是第一个答应的而已
You're just the first one who said yes.
-我受够了  受够了  -拜托
- I'm done. I'm done - Come on.
求你了  扮演一下巴德  就一两天
Please, just be Bud -- for a couple days.
你可以干些杂活儿  然后或许
You can do some chores, maybe I can
我再呵斥你两句  装得更像点
berate you a little bit to really sell it.
你听不出你的话有多过分吗
Do you hear how insane you sound?
让我干杂活儿
Chores?
好吧  你知道吗
All right, you know what?
你想怎么对付你奶奶随便你
You -- you deal with your grandmother however you want.
-我和莉莉要去找酒店住  -不行
- Lily and I will just go get a hotel room. - No, you can't.
好吧  没酒店就找汽车旅馆或粮仓
Fine. Motel, silo --
什么都行
whatever you got around here.
不  那个警报表示龙卷风这就要来了
No, that alarm means there's a tornado coming right now.
我的天  莉莉在哪里
Oh, god. Well, where's lily?
但愿她不会还在田里
I hope she's not still out in the field.
莉莉
Lil-y-y-y-y!
你不能像唤猪一样地叫她
You can't just call her like a pig!
莉莉
Lil-y-y-y-y-y!
好吧  只能在农场这样叫
Okay, this is just a farm thing,
回到城里大商场可不行
not, like, a mall thing.
-你说什么  城市之声  -快走吧
- What's that, city voice? Hmm? - Just go.
这个缠得真够紧的
This is really in there good.
让她离我远点
Get her off of me.
她身上的傻气要渗透给我了
I'm getting dumb through osmosis.
我才没有渗透这种东西
I don't have osmosis.
太好了  查克把披萨送来了
Oh, great. Chuck's here with the pizza.
歌洛莉亚  你可以去开下门吗
Gloria, can you please get it?
不行  你们两个得对彼此友善点
No. You two be nice to each other
自己解决
and figure it out.
你好  查克
Oh, hey, Chuck.
我没想到你今晚还要工作
I didn't think you'd be working tonight.
你好  你怎么会在这里
Hey. What are you doing here?
这里是我外公的家
Oh, this is my grandfather's house.
后院有游泳池  你会游泳吗
There's a pool. Do you swim?
看你这身材一定会
You look like you swim.
我确实会游
I do.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
你还好吧
You okay?
还好  没事  有点抽筋而已
Oh, yeah. Totally. Just a cramp.
我经常锻炼  稍等一下
I work out. One second.
-你个小...  -闭嘴
- You little... - Shut up.
你好啊
Hey, you.
你好  棕眼美女
Hey, brown eyes.
好的  谢谢  再见
Okay, cool. Thanks. Bye.
再见
Bye!
-干嘛  -闭嘴  笨蛋
- What? - Shut up, dork.
别紧张  亲爱的
Don't be nervous, honey.
没有什么好害怕的
There's nothing to be scared of.
放轻松  妈妈  别把屁股摔了
Take it easy, mama. Don't break a hip.
告诉你吧
I'm telling you right now.
我才不要假装成别人
I am not pretending to be something I'm not,
尤其是当着女儿的面
especially in front of our daughter.
我六年都不能当着你爸的面亲你
Oh, so I can't kiss you in front of your dad for six years,
你就不能为了我忍两天吗
and you can't give me two days?
我们是为了不让老太太难过
We're saving an old lady some unnecessary upset.
为什么不给她多点信任呢
Why don't you give her a little credit?
她说不定比你想的更开明
She might be more open-minded than you think.
你个可爱的小中国娃
Well, you're a cute little Chinese thing.
奶奶  其实她是越南人
Actually, gram, she's, uh, from Vietnam,
她叫莉莉
and her name's Lily.
爸爸  我们还得在这呆多久
Dad, how long do we have to stay down here?
"爸爸"
"Dad"?
好吧  看来真没辙了
Okay, well, I guess there's no way around this.
其  其实
Ac-- actually, ma'am...
她是我家的
...she's my kin.
那你是有个中国妻子咯  巴德
So, you got a Chinese wife, Bud?
不是  我去了趟越南
No, I-I-I went to vietnam,
自己领养了个娃
and I did myself some adopting,
现在我就孤身一人养着她
And now I'm raising her all by my lonesome.
我从没想到有生之年还能见识这种事
Well, I never thought I'd live long enough to see that.
大家都没想到
None of us did.
但我想世上最重要的就是家庭了
But I guess there's nothing more important than family...
不管这家庭是如何建立的
no matter how they come.
您真是太开明了
Well, that is mighty open-minded of you.
有人就不懂分享这种进步
Some folks 'round these parts don't share that progressive--
这种进步的情感
I say progressive-- sensibility.
青菜萝卜  各有所爱
To each his own.
但我确实希望
But I do wish I had another
能有这么个小不点儿来宠爱
little one like that to spoil.
要是我说你确实有个曾孙女呢
What if I told you you did have a great-grandbaby?
-什么  -小卡
- What? - Cam...
没关系  妈妈
It's okay, mama.
要是我说我恋爱了
What if I told you I was in love,
而且我此生从未如此幸福
and that I've never been happier in my entire life,
而且我就要结婚了呢
and that I'm about to get married?
那简直是世上最好的消息
I can't think of anything better.
要是我告诉你我的毕生至爱
And what if I told you the love of my life
就是这个男人呢
is this man standing right here?
难怪上帝要带给我们这场龙卷风
Then I'd know why god sent us this tornado.
该死
Damn.
最初的震惊之后  奶奶缓和了一些
After the initial shock, gram softened a bit.
她甚至同意参加婚礼了
She even agreed to attend the wedding.
举着牌子站在场外抗议
Standing outside with a sign.
慢慢来  米奇尔  慢慢来
Baby steps, Mitchell. Baby steps.
然后  天线就
And... our antenna is...
-重新连上了  -赞
- reattached. - Yes!
这没用啊
Oh, this is useless.
我不想听见这种话
Hey, I don't want to hear talk like that.
想鼓舞士气就想想阿波罗十三号
If you want inspiration, think about Apollo 13.
杰第一次组装这模型的时候也没有放弃
Jay didn't give up when he first put together this model.
这很难很复杂  而且那时候
It was hard and complicated, and back then,
说明书上的字也很小
the print on the instructions was tiny,
可他坚持下去了
but he persevered.
而且  真的阿波罗十三号上的宇航员
Also, the astronauts on the actual Apollo 13
身处险境时也没有放弃
didn't give up when their actual lives were in danger.
是的  但他们有很多人帮忙
Them, too, but they had a lot of other people helping them out.
我们只能靠自己
We're on our own here.
我知道我们需要什么东西
Okay, I figured out what we need
来重新组装这该死的着陆舱了
to reattach that damn landing module.
胶水不行
Glue won't work.
我们需要根非常细的长丝
We need a very thin filament--
比线还细的
thinner than thread.
我知道什么能行
I know what will work.
我得离开一下
Well, I need to go check on something.
我跟我的女伴说我去去就回
I told my date I'd be back in a jiff.
去去就回
Back in a jiff.
只能等了
Nothing to do but wait.
我们为何自己乱了阵脚  菲尔
Why are we making ourselves crazy, Phil?
不知道  我就是不想让杰失望
I don't know. I just hate disappointing Jay so much.
他的确不是容易取悦的人
He is not an easy guy to please.
我知道  可一旦成功就很幸福  是吧
I know, but when you do, it's pretty sweet, ain't it?
必须的
Sure is.
你很幸运有这么个老爸
You're lucky to have a dad like that.
很难不受伤啊  儿子
Hard not to be hurt by that, son.
我怎么以前没发现你喘气这么大声
How have I never noticed how loud you breathe?
别自责了  那需要你
Aw, don't beat yourself up-- that'd require you
注意到你自己以外的事情
to notice something that isn't about you.
天呐  你真失败
Oh, my god, you are such a loser!
我可不能整天跟你在一起
I can't be stuck to you all day!
够了  我听不下去了
Okay, that's it! I cannot listen to this anymore!
我要把你俩剪开
I'm going to cut you two out of there.
不  歌洛莉亚  我的头发
No! Gloria, no! My hair!
-太晚了  -好吧  剪我的就好
- Too late! - Okay, okay! Just cut mine.
没错  剪她的  等等  为什么
Yeah, cut hers! Wait. Why?
反正也没人关心我长什么样
No one cares what I look like, anyway.
你才不是真的这么想
You don't really think that.
多少有一点
Yeah, well, kind of.
你没看到查克看你的眼神吗
You didn't see the way that Chuck was looking at you?
等等  你真觉得我对你是个威胁吗
Wait, you actually think I'm a threat?
我不会说出来的
I'm not gonna say that out loud.
这真窝心
Aww, that's so sweet.
要是我有男朋友
Well, if I ever had a boyfriend,
我绝对不会让他和你独处五秒的
I wouldn't trust him with you for five seconds.
好了  结束吧
Okay. Let's finish this job.
歌洛莉亚  别  不能剪
Gloria, no, you can't cut--
搞定了
And there you go.
就这样  小菜一碟
That's it. That was easy.
你为什么等了一小时才这样做
Why did you wait an hour to do this?
你们为什么等了15年才那么做呢
Why did you wait 15 years to do that?
至少这样  大家的秀发
At least this way, nothing bad happened
都不会受损
to anyone's pretty hair.
女儿  我没听到你进来
Oh, honey. I didn't hear you come in.
-晚上过得如何  -这么说吧
- How was the rest of your night? - Let's see.
在你放了我鸽子之后
After you bailed on me,
衣柜乌托邦的马可一直冲我喋喋不休
Mark from Closetopia yakked my ear off,
还说我长得像海蒂・克鲁姆
and then told me I look like Heidi Klum,
这简直是赤裸裸的挑逗
which is such an obvious come-on.
马可是同性恋
Mark's gay.
这样的话  今晚糟透了
Well, in that case, my night stank.
我没有放你鸽子
And I didn't bail.
这里很多人跟我很熟  他们把我拉走的
I know a lot of people here. They pulled me away.
这睡袍棒极了
Hey, these robes are terrific.
衣柜里有你一件
You know, there's one for you in the closet.
你一定要穿上感受一下
You ought to put it on.
我不想穿浴袍
I don't want a robe.
爸  你今晚是不是在躲我
Dad, were you avoiding me tonight?
我为什么要躲你
Why would I avoid you?
相信我  柔软的像黄油一样
Trust me -- soft, like butter.
就在那里挂着
Right in there.
不要非让我问出口
Don't make me ask.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
20年前你和丽塔
You and Rita 20 years ago --
-没什么  我都知道了  -天呐
- It's okay. I know. - Oh, geez.
我理解  这种事时有发生
I get it. Things happen.
-真的么  -事情过去很久了
- Really? - It was a long time ago.
好吧  感谢理解
Well, I appreciate it.
我只能说我并不以此为傲
I just want to say I'm not proud of it.
如果那时我能像现在这样了解他
If I had known him then like I know him now,
我绝不会试图把菲尔从你身边赶走
I never would have tried to get rid of Phil.
晚安
Good night.
把菲尔赶走  你在说什么
"Get rid of Phil"? What are you talking about?
你又在说什么
What are you talking about?
你和丽塔的婚外情
You and Rita had an affair.
不  我们没有  那也太离谱了
No, we didn't. That's crazy.
好吧  晚安
Well, okay, good night.
把菲尔赶走  你那么说是什么意思
"Get rid of phil" -- what does that even mean?
没什么意思  你们刚开始约会
It doesn't mean anything. You had just started dating.
你知道我一直不喜欢那个家伙
You know I was never hot on the guy.
我让丽塔在德克萨斯州
I told Rita to offer him
给他找了个销售职位
a sales job in Texas.
我记得  但那不是在我们约会的阶段
I remember that, but that wasn't when we were dating.
-我们都订婚了  -那不重要
- We were engaged. - Doesn't matter.
菲尔也没有接受那份工作
Phil didn't take the job anyway.
如果一定要说有什么后果
If anything, my little test
我的小测试证明了他有多爱你
proved how much he loved you.
不用客气  我们明早再谈
You're welcome. We'll talk in the morning.
你怎么能这样  还敢说"不用客气"
Oh, how dare you -- "You're welcom" please.
我无法和你共处一室了
Oh, I can't even be in the same room with you.
-我的外套在哪  -克莱尔
- Where is my coat? - Uh, Claire.
真是不敢相信
Ugh, unbelievable.
我不喜欢我的女婿
"I don't like my son-in-law,
所以我要把他打发到德克萨斯去
so I'm gonna ship him off to Texas."
爸  你这样处理问题真"成熟"
Real mature way to deal with your problems, dad.
-我明白你的意思  -是啊  真成熟
- I get that point. - Yeah. Real mature.
-这样整人也很成熟  -这是传统
- That's real mature, too. - That's tradition.
-那是个骷髅  -在衣橱里  我知道
- It's the skeleton... - In the closet. Oh, I get it.
[skeleton in the closet: 见不得光的秘密]
我非常抱歉  但在你冲出去之前
I'm really sorry, but before you go storming out of here,
你想不想谈谈几年前我接到的
you want to talk about a certain phone call I got
一通移民局打来的电话
from immigration a few years ago?
那时我刚开始和歌洛莉亚约会
I had just started dating Gloria.
他们说有人匿名举报
They were acting on an anonymous tip.
时候不早了
It's very late.
明天还有不少事要做
We have a very big day tomorrow.
克莱尔  我现在越来越喜欢菲尔了
You know, Claire, I've really come to like Phil.
我知道
I know.
而且讽刺的是
And the irony is,
他会很喜欢这个骷髅的梗
he would really love that skeleton gag.
你可以在他身上试试
Try it out on him. You got
明年的会议之前骷髅由你来保管
to take care of that thing till next year.
天哪
Oh, god.
等等  在你关灯之前
Wait, before you turn that out,
我们得确认一下没什么需要谈的了吧
have we talked about everything we need to?
因为我想把一切都说开
'cause I want everything out in the clear here.
是的  没有了
Yeah. We have.
晚安
Good night.
大概15年前我确实和丽塔亲热过一次
I did make out with Rita once about 15 years ago.
晚安
Good night.
好
Okay.
剩下的就是
All that's left...
要把着陆舱连接到驾驶舱上
is to reattach the lander to the command module.
我们只有一次机会  伙计们
We got one shot at this, fellas.
如果失败了 杰一回到家就会发疯的  对吧
If we fail, jay's gonna burn up on re-entry into this house. Am I right?
一次搞定  儿子
Hole in one, son!
谢谢  老爸
Thanks, dad.
孩子们  如果这事搞砸了
Boys, if this thing goes sideways,
我不想你们亲眼看到
I don't want you to be here to see it.
-所以快走  -但爸爸
- So go on. - But, dad --
不  听我的
No, you listen to me!
好的  菲尔
Okay, Phil.
好吧  菲利普
Okay, Philip.
稳一点
Steady.
他要开始了
He's locked in.
现在不是紧张的时候
Not now, nerves.
稳住
Hold.
当个英雄
Be a hero.
带她回家
Bring her home.
我看我还是打车走吧
I guess I'll call a cab.
再见  珍宁
So long, Jeanine.
难道  这是
Is it? Is --
完成了
It is!
成功溅落
Splashdown!
狗娘养的  他成功了
Son of a bitch, he did it.
歌洛莉亚  快来
Yeah! Gloria, get in here!
快来
There we go!
-爸  你成功了  -是啊  成功了
- Dad, you did it! - Yes, I did!
太棒了  太棒了
I love it! I love it!
太棒了
I love it!
菲尔  亲爱的  快上床
Phil, honey. Come to bed.
这浴袍滑的像黄油一样
This robe feels like butter.
太怀念了  亲爱的
I missed this, honey.
这瑜伽课可真是物超所值啊
That yoga's really paying off.
悠着点  宝贝
Hey, whoa. Slow down, baby.
发动机可还没烧热呢
You can't gun a cold engine.
但如果你...那床上的是...
But if you're -- then who's --
你什么时候发现的
When did you know?
它没有抱怨我穿着袜子
When it didn't complain about my socks.
你检查过衣橱了  是不是
You checked the closet, didn't you?
每晚睡前都会检查
Every night before bed.
我真的不懂  这好傻
I really don't understand it. It's so silly.
我是说  如果真的有人想杀你
I mean, if somebody really wanted to kill you,
很明显他们会藏在床下
obviously they'd just hide under the bed.
晚安
Good night.
妈的
Damn it.